

Profile

I am a generalist games programmer with nearly **7 years of programming experience**. In my time at The Breda University of Applied Sciences, I worked on many different tasks, from **Mod.io** integration to **loading trenchbroom level files**.

Employment History

Junior app developer, I4things, Herten

2020 - 2021

I4things was a company that specialized in creating software solutions for the management of IOT devices. While working for I4things me and my team created a control panel application that made use of the **in-house SDK** and the **Android SDK** using the **Kotlin** programming language to allow for the management of IOT devices.

This includes turning them on and off, reading their status, showing notifications about the status of your devices, and integrating an alarm system that uses the sensors to determine wether to sound an alarm or not.

Intern web developer, Bertels b.v, Ospel

2018 - 2019

While interning at Bertels b.v I worked as a web developer, my workload consisted of supporting the now offline greensensation website. My job was to add new content as requested by the product owner. To do this I made use of **HTML**, **CSS**, **javascript**, **jQuery**, and **bootstrap**.

Education

Games Programming, Breda University of Applied Sciences, Breda

2021 - PRESENT

In my current education, I am learning how to write functional and efficient code for video games and video game development tools. Here we work exclusively with the C++ programming language. So far I have learned about the following: math for video games, C++, 2D and 3D game concepts, videogame graphics, and working in a development team. One of the main points of focus in this education is needing to do your own research on the topics you are expected to learn about with support provided in the form of lectures and feedback.

Software developer, Fontys, Eindhoven

2020 - 2021

I did this education for one year between my previous and my current education. Like Gilde Opleidingen, Fontys keeps its program more focused on general programming with specialization happening later on in the education. Here I mainly improved my knowledge of what I learned at Gilde Opleidingen with the inclusion of C++ for embedded system programming.

Application and media developer, Gilde opleidingen, Roermond

2017 - 2020

This education is focused on teaching the broader concepts of programming while applying them to the field of web development. Here I learned about the basics of programming while using the following languages: HTML, CSS, javascript, PHP, C#,

Details

monseigneur nolensplein 33 Breda, 4812JD Netherlands 0613275048 <u>kittyhwScheres@gmail.com</u>

Links

Portfolio site

Linkedin

Hobbies

Next to programming I also enjoy the following activities:

- Singing
- Playing video games
- Watching anime

Skills

C++

C#

Unreal engine 5

Mod.io

OpenXR

Languages

Dutch

English

SQL, and **C++**. Next to these languages, I was also taught to use libraries like **jQuery**, **Bootstrap**, **ASP.net**, and **SDL2**.

Game projects

On The Bubble

On the Bubble is a custom engine game project. The goal of the project is to create a spiritual successor to the Monkeyball games with the inclusion of a custom-level editor. The game will be playable on both **Windows** and **PlayStation 5**, but it will only be published on Windows through **Steam**.

In this project, I take the role of **generalist programmer**. The work I am doing for this project consists of implementing the **Mod.io SDK** for the uploading and downloading of custom levels. I also support the development of the level editor. Some of the work I did for this was the creation of the **undo-redo** system.

Camp Champ

Camp Champ is a local multiplayer party game where 2 teams challenge each other in a game of capture the flag. During the production of this game, I was both a **gameplay programmer** and the **programming lead** for this project.

On the gameplay side, I implemented the systems surrounding the capturing of the flags. I also worked on the team selection screen.

Most of my time was spent on lead tasks. These include:

- Creating builds of our game
- Providing tech support for both Perforce and Jira
- Providing general tech support for the project
- Keeping communication within the project team flowing
- Conflict resolution between teammebers.

Custom FPS engine

During my education at buas I worked on a custom FPS engine with **6 other programmers**. This engine allows for the creation of first-person shooter games with levels created in the TrenchBroom level editor. The games created with this engine run on both **Windows and PlayStation 5**.

While working on this project I took the role of **engine programmer**. My main contributions here were the implementation of reading BSP files that have been generated by TrenchBroom. I also implemented the Bullet physics library for the collision handling in the engine.